And I will call the order, the regular scheduled meeting of the state council from Monday, December 16th, 2020, forward.
Do you put the can put on scheduled personal premises? We have none.
Three please list.
Most two proof.
Sorry.
Estep.
Hi.
Jones.
Barnes.
Hi.
Parker.
Four minutes from the November 18th, 2020, four regular meeting.
Motion to prove.
Hi.
Parker.
Five.
Green gateway.
Pullman.
Outside organization update and discussion.
Missile masters.
I'm trying to first thank you.
Let's a shut.
Yeah.
Just tissue.
All right.
I've got several pages in front of you.
And there is two pages that is Pelavand.
There is two that are our pick transportation.
I have stable both of the pick winds together, both of the Pelavand.
Together.
I'm going to go to this sheet because this one I can actually read the numbers on.
The chart looks good, but I can't read the numbers.
We have done a total.
I did July's numbers through November because we have finished November.
So I was able to give you the numbers for all of them.
In July we did a total level 1125 trips.
Now I did not put it on the sheet that compared to last year at this time.
We're up about 300 trips per month.
So just to give you a little bit of idea where we were last year at this time.
August we did 1130 September 1171.
October 1176 and November 955.
That drop in November was because we had three holidays.
And there was one day we closed because of the weather.
I think it was like November 4th, November 5th.
Something like that.
There was bad storms coming.
So we shut down early.
So that is why we had to drop of to 955 on that month.
Now you can see that medical is of course still the top.
I mean they will, I don't think we'll ever surpass the number that medical does.
But employment was behind that.
So we have a great number of people that use it for employment as well.
Pick transportation.
We finally have a solid driver up here.
So we're open up here six days a week now.
And it is allowed us to pick up some,
especially in the last three months.
I would say that July we did 59 trips for the month.
August we did 53 September 62 October 87 and November 62.
Our ridership is continuing to increase there.
One major change we made this year actually replaced a couple employees as how I'll put it.
And we replaced it with one driver.
that driver does more trips than the other two did combined. So it has allowed us to really increase our
ridership up here. We've got a solid team up here. Actually the best team we have in Pelevian
is up here in Miami now. So we are able to really accommodate the trips that we're needed now.
We have had one issue with phones, but that has since been resolved and it has been fixed.
So our phone system is up and running like it should be. So that has allowed us to increase
with that. Now one thing on this one sheet, you'll notice on this one here, it does the Miami
Booking Method and it says App and Hall Center. You'll notice that October when we had our problem with
our phones, our app usage went up. So people were still able to get their rides. We actually had more
booked in that month than any other month. And it was because we had the app. So we were really
happy with that. And proud of the fact that the ridership for the app usage actually went up quite a bit.
Do you guys have any questions for me? I just want to make one call that. Thank you very much for this.
We've been asking for it for a long time. And then we finally got. So thank you.
Well, as if Gil will like the Miami reminder, I will happily give this to you. I am not the greatest in
brain right now. But how often are you guys wanting it? Quarterly? Quarterly? Okay, so that's a easy.
Great. Awesome. Okay. So thank you for your work. If we do appreciate it. Like Kevin said, we've been asking
for a little while and finally started to get it. Communication is good. I would like to try to build a good team here.
And I think that's probably reflecting in the number. Yes, absolutely. The three guys that we have here now.
And of course, we have a video our guy as well that the three guys that we have for the city are amazing.
And they will do anything anybody ask. It's a great team. For sure. Great. Thank you.
Six. Here of authorization for the city manager's side. The acceptance letter award contract.
Certificate of authorized signatures. And notice to proceed for rural economic action plan to reap.
By actually year 24 grant after legal review.
Thank you. This is a housekeeping matter. We did apply for the brief grant. You all approved the
application. I should have had on the agenda item to have the city manager signed once it was awarded.
But I did not. So I needed to bring it back to you. And then after legal review, we would like to ask you to
have authorized the city manager to sign it once legal has reviewed it. We have to get it back to
grant gateway by 1230.
612.
Good help her.
Motion 2.
It seems worn shirt.
This gives you everything you need.
Yes.
He's seven.
Two, five.
Five.
Seven.
I don't contract no for as needed.
I agree.
Rock.
See 23.
That's for tonight.
With Kim Stone.
That'd be the same.
Motion to approve.
Can we approve?
Motion 7 through 9.
Yes, you can.
Second.
I made the 7 through 9.
Motion.
I.
All right.
Jones.
High.
Thank you.
You're staying on this one too.
No.
We just approved 7 through 9.
Yeah.
He's on 10 then.
Oh, sorry.
I saw Chuck.
I didn't see brunch.
Or been C24-97.
I'm going to try to stay for as a corporate and replace the wooden general floor at six in the amount of
$145,600.
As regular by staff, I'm going to put the contract contingent upon the submission of all required contract documents.
You're related signing authority to city manager for his designated need.
Yes.
I hear in council.
We saw proposals to select a wooden floor company to replace the wooden floor at the Civic Center.
We sent this out.
The RFPs.
Two companies came in.
HDI enterprises and tri-state floors.
The lowest bidder.
And HDI came in at 179-548.
Tri-state floor came in at 125-600.
Chuck here will be able to answer any questions.
And by the way, Chuck took this project on.
And I've never seen a scope of the floor and everything that it takes to make a good solicitation.
You did a great job, but you guys might have some questions for him.
Some of the details on the floor and everything else.
And what we need, we need your approval to award-try state floor of the business at the Civic Center.
You have any pictures of what California but now?
Once we get this in a hurry, we'll work on that.
So you'll bring it back to see what's going to look like.
They've done any other floors in the area that you see.
They're back to done an online one or two other floors.
They did a good job.
So on things they've done for us and they've been issues and if so or their responses or
Depending on the logo that you guys use, is that gonna fluctuate price or it's already included in the price
Potion to approve contract for trust state second
All right, I love 125 to 12 reimburse final housing authority $200,000 and allow the council
He managed the pilot payments received into the number of four twenty seven go sinking fund from this point forward
And if I want to see three senior center department in the senior center fund moving the applicable estimate revenues and expenditures
Accounts that will be managed by the policy three library receiving and expanding the awarded health
Literacy fund our grant fire proceeding and expanding the awarded AFG grant purchase nine sets let's turn out here
You know we read all this or it's on the agenda, you don't need you can just call it
I
Especially like that you stumbled up or literacy
I felt for you
Okay, so this does seven things the city council is over we have thirty funds thirty little companies
The city council manages twenty seven of those funds this affects four of those funds
I know there is a
You're working on a contract with the mind of housing authority that all this does is allow you to pay them the 200,000 that is kind of on the table right now
Even if you go less you can you don't have to pay the full 200 it just gives you a budget to pay it if you want to and pilot me
payment in blue of taxes, that's what they've done for years and years of wealth since
I think that's 60s.
The second thing it does, it allows the 501c3 senior citizens, Inc, to have a budget.
So now we're going to have two budgets.
We're going to have the city's senior center budget, and that will be like the reef grants,
the sea grants, rental revenues, and what this does is creates this other budget that
the 501c3 is over their membership fees, you know, in a way grant, and any other grants
they might get because they're a 501c3.
So that this creates this grant, the 501, a not grant budget, sorry.
It allows the library to recede in and expend their $5,000 health literacy grant.
It allows the fire to recede in and expend an AFG grant for that turnout gear.
It allows PD to use two different checks for insurance recovery to repair some vehicles.
It transfers a, we got a USDA grant, part of that was because of you, MSUA purchases.
So the part that was part of that is going to be transferred back to MSUA, and then it also allows
Parks and Rec to use, we have a dollar 50 rec fee, and that builds up, and we're going to use
a 1026,000 to pay for the gym floor.
And that last slide, this says that the gym floor that was flooded, but the insurance claim was denied,
why they didn't have it.
It's about that.
But even with the drainage ditch there, most two proofs.
Yeah, five.
Jones, five.
Orange, five.
So whole parker.
Five.
Thanks, Jill.
12.
Oakland Municipal Retirement Fund, Master of the Fund, Benefit Plan is joined here, agreement in
order of 24, dash of 0, 20, 24, dash of 0, 20, 24, dash of 0, so basically what this is for
is about every six years, our retirement plan has to do updates to stay in compliance with
the IRS regulations, and that's what this is.
It's the updated plan today.
being compliance with the IRS and each municipality that is a member of the OKMRF has to have their governing body approve it, so that's what we're here for.
So this is the new piece scheduled for the 2025, it'll take effect January 2025 and basically it is a 4.724.7% increase in the fee schedule, which would be the same as the last one.
Every year our TPI negotiates and a new contract with any of the healthcare people that are part of our network.
So just to kind of put a dollar amount to it so you'll understand, we had it.
So in the last fiscal year we paid premium hospital a little over $200 and $4,000.
So with this increase, if everything stayed the same when we had the same claims, it's about a $9,600 increase in the physician fees.
But it's I mean it's to stay in the frame of network and negotiate it down as far as I can negotiate it down so.
Motion to approve.
Thank you.
Coach.
Aye.
Jones.
Parker.
Fourteen orders.
Twenty, twenty, twenty, twenty, forty, twenty, twenty, twenty, twenty, twenty, twenty, twenty, twenty, twenty, twenty, twenty, twenty.
So we have a lot of libraries of the code of ordinances providing.
Separability providing for collecting provisions for building all.
Complenty of ordinances establishing an effective date regarding.
They make up and purpose of the library board.
So council.
The library number one was we expand.
That by as we go, we're.
Fibrating.
The thought was that we brought in some other people still in the majority of them have to be from my,
I know if we brought in other people who rest in the communist palace.
One of the main goals of this name, that the other is the ordinance as it was written,
wasn't real clear that they were an advisory board, as opposed to a autonomous board,
so we just wanted to clean that language up.
And because it is such a short chapter in our woman's,
these two.
But in that 194 page fee schedule, we just had to read.
This doesn't have to be taken before the county commissioners or anything,
because it is in the county also over doing well.
The facility, at least the facility right now, is solely in my,
if we expand to another facility, another physical location in the county,
what it is that they're wanting to do.
Gotcha.
That's the way that the committee.
He said five to five, but this is a six to five.
Oh, a six to nine.
Because that's still a bit enough to get it where she needs to be.
Yeah.
We want the majority to be from,
that opens and bring up some of the money from outside just a city,
so it could bring some money from the county or,
so you're saying five members have to be from the city of my wife.
Motion to prove.
Jones.
Burns.
He said.
Hi.
Parker.
Is it saying there's somewhere, I'm looking,
but that five members have to be from my wife.
That being.
50 is authorized director of finance to close cash CDs accounts that Edward Jones under the senior center department budget and deposit with drawn phones and to senior citizens
and check again
So I'll be playing the part of Jennifer tonight
Last Wednesday at the senior center board meeting they voted to recommend to the council to withdraw these funds that Edward Jones and deposit it into the checking account
The amount as of November 29th is 34,975 62
She will then be bringing later
Recommendation from that at the same advisory board on what to do with any additional money as they could use to reinvest
So we're just going to see we get the best deal at primary investing
So it's 34,975 62
So I'm going to show you two things that some of their advisory board will be in control of and spend how they will or right now at the money belongs to the sick
And so it's part of what she was describing as being in the city budget as opposed to that I don't want to see
Second
E step
Jones, abstain
16 other new business
If any which is represents posting this agenda
17 staff reports
18 mayor
Council meeting announcements
We had a great Christmas parade
Man
Was that the most like floats we'd ever had
I think it's pretty close
It's got to be the most vehicle
That's what it was
It's 87
But there was like 12 cars for just the boys and girls club
I'd say there was more people on sidewalks than I've seen in a long time
There was a lot of people with the parade
A lot of people
A lot more candy this year
That 80 pounds of candy because I ran out last year
There's a lot more
I still ran out
Before I got them
So there was a lot of people down there
Did you have them?
I didn't know
I was great walking up and down the thing and just seeing all the people everywhere
Another thing I complained about was the trucks
cars that were parked on the side that made it challenging.
Or the people that kept coming off the, well, that's always going to happen.
But for the band, I was trying to get people back because I didn't happen.
That's all good.
It was a great event.
Good, good bunch of stuff going on downtown.
I love where we're going with Christmas and everything downtown.
Absolutely.
I'll tell you, I got a message from a girl that said her mother was here from Oregon.
And she said the message that her mom fell in love with her and downtown was that great for Christmas.
So that's good.
It was to, to all you and your people that helped do that.
So we appreciate it because people come downtown and they love it.
So.
30 minutes left in the sipping shop.
So if you give her a theater writer here, we'll go for a sipping shop.
So all the shops are still open, drink specials, deals, go shit shop on Main Street tonight.
And as you can see, Brian and I are wearing Popeye Studies and Tyler, who's supposed to wear his.
He was scared and he didn't taste bad.
Dockles, but we had lunch, Friday, afternoon with the representatives of Popeye's and Tyler got free sandwich.
Keep on Stu.
So F.I.
He has got a bunch.
Thank you.
But they'll be starting soon.
They got all their paperwork turned in and I think they're just waiting on a few of the other
construction loan things, but already owned the property.
So hopefully after the first year, they'll get rolling on that Popeye's location.
And hopefully, by next week, we may be able to tell you about a couple more things we've got that'll
be coming to town.
So lots of good stuff happening, but again, we credit our city employees for all your work, because
your work's been noticed from people outside our community and they're wondering their businesses
here.
So thank you, guys.
It's payin' off.
City of Manor Communications.
Just when I wish everybody a Merry Christmas and I happy new year, and I'm really excited
stuff coming in January.
We're going to have a presentation on our landfill, you know, versus transportation, instead of
being able to be information on that, that our rate studies will be done by then, so we'll
present that in the angry tube.
So I heard there was like a elf making it to a round of the city today too.
Yeah, I've heard that new.
Yeah.
Thank you, Mayor and two from Ganner, Grand Gate Ways Excuse Me, too.
So thank you, they're helping us right now on a couple things.
A lot of things.
Thank you.
Thank you for your attention.
Thank you for helping us some future grants.
So, we appreciate your partnership.
We really do.
And then, it's came a long way over the last year or two, and you got a great little
appreciate it.
And the last thing I want to wish for being to get lucky, because I'm going to be a new
It's a good editing.
It's a great job.
It's a great collaboration.
I'll go one request.
You take that, you know, fine with you.
You do not leave it
yeah.
It's just a secure session.
Just so you know, you're learning a session then.
Somebody gets off topic because you get a stay-off topic
because there's a secure session.
or somebody says something that's not on topic, we get the old flag for them on us, it stops.
So, that's dunkle usually, though.
No, it's not always.
You don't, okay, it's okay.
If I don't do use going to be like this, I'll make you hit your hand on my school bus.
I said it.
Yes, sir.
All right, so that's one of these.
This may be continued from Calth Chamber to Rick being the staff room for the purpose of your second session.
Wow.